guys this looks like a fun one it was
posted by my math Solutions so let's
solve it we have two rectangles in a
triangle that we know the area and we're
trying to find the area of this last
triangle I think there's a lot of
different ways to solve this but I want
to share with you what I ended up doing
I called this side x this side y this
side Z and this side W let's start with
this rectangle x times Z is equal to 15.
and after we divide both sides by X we
get Z is equal to 15 over X and if we go
to this rectangle y times W is equal to
12. divide both sides by y now we get W
is equal to 12 over y so now let's
update the Z to make it 15 over X and
let's update the W to make it 12 over Y
and then let's get rid of this stuff now
let's look at this triangle the area of
a triangle is one half base times height
so this is going to be one half x times
y equals nine and after we multiply both
sides by 2 on the left hand side we get
x y and on the right hand side we get
18. this looks important so let's put a
box around it now we're ready for the
question mark since it is the area of a
triangle it's going to be equal to one
half base times height if we turn our
heads sideways we can think of the base
is equal to 15 over X and the height is
12 over Y and now we're just multiplying
fractions 1 times 15 times 12 is equal
to 180 and 2 times x times Y is equal to
2xy and we could simplify this 180
divided by 2 is equal to 90 and then we
still have the X Y earlier we figured
out that x times y was equal to 18 so
I'm going to change this into an 18 and
then 90 divided by 18 is equal to 5 and
it's going to be centimeters squared and
that's the answer to our question the
area of this blue triangle is equal to 5
centimeters squared let's make it bigger
and put a box around it how exciting